<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>∆ U = Q - W</title>
    <description>Long Form Jekyll theme built with SASS / COMPASS / SUSY</description>
    <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 10:51:08 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2015 10:51:08 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Reading RailsRoad</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;date:   2015-12-15
&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;hat is Rails? Think of it as an app assembly program.  It’s built using the ruby language (thus Ruby on Rails), and is one of the most efficient ways to build amazing web apps.  Intrigued? Good read on.  Not interested… well then, movalongnothingtoseehere. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, rails is a program that’s been built using ruby, which takes html, ruby, and javascript works some neat-o magic and presto-chango you create a web application that a regular, non-programming, person can interact with in their web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it’s not nearly that simple.  The reason rails works so well is that it requires very specific methods and syntax.  Think of it this way, every single web application has several things in common, html heads, JavaScript interfaces, CSS formatting, the list goes on and on.   Rails knows this so each of these bits (and many more) are built into the framework.  The framework requires you, the developer, to use best practices to create each aspect of the application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By requiring best practices or conventions be followed, the construction of each application is streamlined, every application  is easily readable by other engineers, and since each part of the app should nearly look like every app you’ve ever built, debugging is a snap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This simplicity comes at a cost, however.  To use rails well you have to know the exact way to create the functionality you’re looking for.  Additionally, if there’s a weakness in the fundamentals of rails, well then, there are a lot of apps that share that weakness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fastidiousness, and potential security concerns aside (to be raised in a later post), if you’re interested in learning the fastest, most efficient, effective, and accepted method to build webapps, you may want to look into learning rails.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;date:   2015-12-15
&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;W&lt;/span&gt;hat is Rails? Think of it as an app assembly program.  It’s built using the ruby language (thus Ruby on Rails), and is one of the most efficient ways to build amazing web apps.  Intrigued? Good read on.  Not interested… well then, movalongnothingtoseehere. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/Rails/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/Rails/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>JavaStick</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;date:   2015-12-15
&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;friend of mine once described the difference between JavaScript and Ruby as the difference between driving a stick-shift car vs an automatic, and nowhere is that more clear than in looping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Ruby, in order to loop you simply have to choose the method through with you want to loop (eg. Each, for, while, etc …), connect it with your object, and that’s really it. So looping though a simple array in Ruby would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;each&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;variable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;|&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;variable&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JavaScript on the other hand forces you to break it apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There isn’t a simple ‘each’ function in JavaScript. Instead, if you want to loop through each value in an array, you need to think about that as a separate problem to work through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know JavaScript keeps track of an index, good. You can call objects by their index, good. You can assign variables numerical values, and can change those values based on certain circumstances, good. JavaScript will stop the loop when certain circumstances are met, good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on that you know you can create a variable which represents the number of values in the array (an index variable), and will move from one value to the next, using the index variable. If you set a termination condition (eg. When the index variable is equal to the number of elements), the loop will reach that condition and stop, and you will have iterated over each element in your array. Using the same array as above, that would look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;5&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;array&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;+=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the i variable is what’s keeping track of where the program is in the loop, and as long as i &amp;lt; array.length, the loop will continue. A bit more stick-shifty than Ruby, eh…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;date:   2015-12-15
&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;friend of mine once described the difference between JavaScript and Ruby as the difference between driving a stick-shift car vs an automatic, and nowhere is that more clear than in looping.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/Java/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/Java/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Hashing Away at Arrays</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;rrays and hashes, are two important aspects of programming.  But for some reason there’s a fair amount of confusion regarding the distinction between the two, which completely makes sense seeing as they&#39;re both arrays... WHAAAAA?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, my incredulous friend, as far as Ruby is concerned hashes are a type of array.  I mean, sure they look different and require slightly different syntaxes to use, but to use a mediocre metaphore, they&amp;#39;re different chapters in the same book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, as far as using them is concerened, there are some very important differences between hashes and arrays.  Aside from the syntax differences, hashes and arrays are really quite different.  An array is an ordered list.  It can have numbers, letters, words, really anything in it.  A comma separates each item and each item can be called by its number within the array (though the first item has the 0 place).  Long story made somewhat longer, imaine an array as a normal to-do list or grocery list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hash on the other hand, is a bit more like an inventory. Imagine you’re at a car dealership and they have hatchbacks, trucks, sedans, and convertibles. Great, that’s all great info, but if you wanted to further narrow it down to blue convertibles that get greater than 30 mpg, you would could find exactly that car, if you had input all the information into a hash, and called up your desired attributes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So perhaps the best way to think about it is that an array is a simple list, while a hash is a more ordered array.  I hope you can get away with your knowledge of arrays when you next chat about hashes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;A&lt;/span&gt;rrays and hashes, are two important aspects of programming.  But for some reason there’s a fair amount of confusion regarding the distinction between the two, which completely makes sense seeing as they&#39;re both arrays... WHAAAAA?!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/Arrays/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/Arrays/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Be a Git</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;o, you’ve fallen down the CSS rabbit hole to my fine blog.  Welcome, it’s busy and confusing down here.  At this point you’ve composed your content, have an idea of how you want the site to look, and begun fiddling around in CSS.  All of a sudden you’re struck with some seemingly identical terms.  Margin, Border, and Padding.   Well don’t worry, I’m here to suss out the differences for you.  And unlike other blogs I’m going to do this without any figures or visual aids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to imagine that I’m hanging up a framed picture.  The wall upon which I’m hanging the picture is window where the content will be.  That wall may or may not have been painted, it may have other pictures on it, it may even be a wall no one will ever see, but for the sake of this discussion, none of that matters, it’s main function is to be the place where your picture (content goes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The margin is arguably the most important positioning element.  Using our analogy, it’s the space between the frame and the edge of the wall, and everything else that’s hung there.  It isn’t part of the picture itself, but knowing how your picture relates to everything else is absolutely crucial to making your wall look the way you want.  In effect your margin ensures that your design element is spaced the way you want it with regards to everything else on the wall (page).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The border of your design element is your frame.  If you’re looking to add something simple it may be completely invisible (like hanging a poster on a dorm room wall), or it may be ornate (hanging a picture at the Louvre). While the border is important to the overall spacing of the content, most importantly, it represents the separation between the element you’re moving around, and the rest of the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Padding is always within the border and is any amount of space between the actual content and border.  Much like the border, this may not exist in any visual way, but as a design concept it’s always a factor.  If you look at most framed pictures there’s some amount of blank space between the picture and the frame, that’s the padding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margin, border, and padding are all indispensable, and utterly distinct aspects to designing any website. Understanding how they’re different, and relate to one another is the difference between a beautiful and pleasant website, and a 15 year-old’s 2003 MySpace page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;S&lt;/span&gt;o, you’ve fallen down the CSS rabbit hole to my fine blog.  Welcome, it’s busy and confusing down here.  At this point you’ve composed your content, have an idea of how you want the site to look, and begun fiddling around in CSS.  All of a sudden you’re struck with some seemingly identical terms.  Margin, Border, and Padding.   Well don’t worry, I’m here to suss out the differences for you.  And unlike other blogs I’m going to do this without any figures or visual aids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/CSS/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/CSS/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Be a Git</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;V&lt;/span&gt;esion cntrol, version cntrol, version control, is crucial to programming.  Put simply, as changes are made to the code they are saved along with a message describing what implementation of the code is meant to accomplish. This provides coders with the tools required to effectively turn on and off any change that has been made to the code.  Maintaining good version control hygiene means as bugs crop up, you can return to the most recent functioning code, locate what’s changed between the functional and non-functional code, and repair it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you are first learning to code, you will largely be working on simple code by yourself.  And while you can see the advantages of version control in that environment, it really becomes crucial once you begin working on large teams on massive projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Of course, I already save my changes…’ you may be saying.  Well that’s good, but version control is more akin to a meta-save than the ‘command s’ you’re used to.  The main tool for this job is called Git.  Git is a program that you run from your command line that saves all the changes you made to the project along with a message describing what the change is meant to accomplish.  Additionally it knows exactly where those changes were made, points them out, and fixes all your bugs for you… well not the last bit, but those first two makes the process of fixing the bugs much easier job for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, Git, works in concert with GitHub.  GitHub is sort of like cloud storage for your code.  Functionally, however, GitHub is a bit more like a giant repository for coders everywhere.  Sure, it’s nice to have your code stored off your computer, at this point we’re all well versed in the benefits of cloud storage, but the real benefit comes from the openness of GitHub.   Coders will often upload their projects to GitHub and make it publically available so fellow coders can access it and incorporate it into their projects (This website for example).  This collaborative environment is a cornerstone of the coding community, and will be immensely useful as you develop your career as a developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So really what I’m saying, is good version control makes you a valued, participant in one of the worlds largest collaborative communities. Pretty neat eh!?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;V&lt;/span&gt;esion cntrol, version cntrol, version control, is crucial to programming.  Put simply, as changes are made to the code they are saved along with a message describing what implementation of the code is meant to accomplish. This provides coders with the tools required to effectively turn on and off any change that has been made to the code.  Maintaining good version control hygiene means as bugs crop up, you can return to the most recent functioning code, locate what’s changed between the functional and non-functional code, and repair it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/Git/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/Git/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Example Post Formatting</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;urabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Donec sed odio dui. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Heading 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Heading 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Heading 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Heading 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5&gt;Heading 5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Heading 6&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Donec sed odio dui. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Unordered List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longer List Item

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nested List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nested Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Ordered List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longer List Item

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nested OL Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another Nested Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List Item&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Definition List&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Coffee&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Black hot drink&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;Milk&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;White cold drink&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Donec sed odio dui. Cras justo odio, dapibus ac facilisis in, egestas eget quam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras justo odio, dapibus ac facilisis in, egestas eget quam. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Aenean eu leo quam. Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa justo sit amet risus. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa justo sit amet risus. Aenean eu leo quam. Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue laoreet rutrum faucibus dolor auctor. Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Maecenas faucibus mollis interdum. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;C&lt;/span&gt;urabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper. Donec sed odio dui. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/example-post-formatting/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/example-post-formatting/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Featured Image</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahamontes lanterne rouge normandie belgium. Fred paris-nice arrivere, for omnium commissaire ronde van vlaanderen horizontally stiff but vertically compliant muur, valkenberg jens paris-roubaix. Meyrueis belleville cavendish bianchi, rochefort echelon in soigneur ten dam omloop het volk, bettini aerts! Tour de mont aigoual cat among the pigeons rekelberg omloop het nieuwsblad paris-nice, dwars door vlaanderen coppi the colnago knockteberg anduze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaperij lanterne rouge musette rund um koln bruges thor smash, geraardsbergen riis petacchi molteni pedaling squares. Virenque vande velde, valkenberg gutter pantani parcours gaul domestique, tilford campagnolo around madone. Bruyneel criterium ritte, gorgeous george the trousselier feed zone bruges nokere koerse, parcours gilbert garin? Anquetil valkenberg bettini cat among the pigeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campagnolo the hors delai de wolf as the toto turns venga venga venga, sanchez nys. Pantani hell of the north oude kwaremont nitto koppenberg, tiegemberg van steenbergen lombardie flamme rouge lemond e3 prijs vlaanderen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planckaert berg ter stene freire gorgeous george in rouleur derby, vaughters fabianese omloop het volk rouleur play rouleur derby. Bottechia petacchi, milan-san remo van summeren off the back cutters the cassette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nyvelocity pyrenees vande velde merckx. La fleche wallonne fixie pau, with muur hors categorie boonen aerts operacion puerto, topsport vlaanderen pereiro randonneur. This greek text is produced by rouleur derby, almost certainly the best fantasy cycling game in the world snob trousselier col du galibier, flanders venga venga venga suitcase of courage cutters kolobnev molenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/featured-image/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/featured-image/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Post With A Code Snippet</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Y&lt;/span&gt;ou&#39;ll find this post in your `_posts` directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the `-w` switch) to see your changes! To add new posts, simply add a file in the `_posts` directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&amp;#39;s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Y&lt;/span&gt;ou&#39;ll find this post in your `_posts` directory - edit this post and re-build (or run with the `-w` switch) to see your changes! To add new posts, simply add a file in the `_posts` directory that follows the convention: YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/code-snippet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/code-snippet/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Figure With A Caption</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahamontes lanterne rouge normandie belgium. Fred paris-nice arrivere, for omnium commissaire ronde van vlaanderen horizontally stiff but vertically compliant muur, valkenberg jens paris-roubaix. Meyrueis belleville cavendish bianchi, rochefort echelon in soigneur ten dam omloop het volk, bettini aerts! Tour de mont aigoual cat among the pigeons rekelberg omloop het nieuwsblad paris-nice, dwars door vlaanderen coppi the colnago knockteberg anduze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/touring.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Fig1. - This is an example figcaption&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;figure&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;/assets/img/touring.jpg&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;alt=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;figcaption&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Fig1. - This is an example figcaption&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kaperij lanterne rouge musette rund um koln bruges thor smash, geraardsbergen riis petacchi molteni pedaling squares. Virenque vande velde, valkenberg gutter pantani parcours gaul domestique, tilford campagnolo around madone. Bruyneel criterium ritte, gorgeous george the trousselier feed zone bruges nokere koerse, parcours gilbert garin? Anquetil valkenberg bettini cat among the pigeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Campagnolo the hors delai de wolf as the toto turns venga venga venga, sanchez nys. Pantani hell of the north oude kwaremont nitto koppenberg, tiegemberg van steenbergen lombardie flamme rouge lemond e3 prijs vlaanderen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planckaert berg ter stene freire gorgeous george in rouleur derby, vaughters fabianese omloop het volk rouleur play rouleur derby. Bottechia petacchi, milan-san remo van summeren off the back cutters the cassette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nyvelocity pyrenees vande velde merckx. La fleche wallonne fixie pau, with muur hors categorie boonen aerts operacion puerto, topsport vlaanderen pereiro randonneur. This greek text is produced by rouleur derby, almost certainly the best fantasy cycling game in the world snob trousselier col du galibier, flanders venga venga venga suitcase of courage cutters kolobnev molenberg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;L&lt;/span&gt;orem ipsum thor smash liege-bastogne-liege landbouwkrediet ombregt krabbe, rouleur derby is for lovers bonk giro gilbert bidon. Driedaagse de panne-koksijde monte paschi eroica, nevele gimondi berendries off the back cassette tenbosse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/figure-with-caption/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/figure-with-caption/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>CSS CheatSheet</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Q&lt;/span&gt;uick and dirty CSS cheatsheet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cheatsheet.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=http://www.lesliefranke.com/files/reference/csscheatsheet.html&gt; Leslie Franke&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p class=&quot;intro&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dropcap&quot;&gt;Q&lt;/span&gt;uick and dirty CSS cheatsheet&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/image-in-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/RNBrandt/RNBrandt.github.io/blog/image-in-post/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
